#### Sonali Agarwal

Permanent Address: 698, Shastri Nagar, Ajmer, Rajasthan, 305001

Email ID: <u>agarwalsonali0297@gmail.com</u>   <b>Mobile No</b> : 8239911044
LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sonali-agarwal-176a4a161/
PROFILE SUMMARY
A competent professional with over <u>4 years</u> of experience in Purchase & Supply chain activities which include Export and Import material activity, material procurement, RM purchasing, Vendor Management Material Planning, Forecasting & Financial Planning and Analysis, and/or Budgeting.
WORK EXPERIENCE

## Import – Export Officer – Purchase & Supply Chain Department

Dyna Automation Pvt Ltd, Ahmedabad

Oct 2018 - Till Date

Company Profile (Brief): Dyna Automation Pvt Ltd. is the largest hydraulic distributor in India operating for more than 30 years now. The company mainly focused on hydraulic solution providers to the chemical and Sugar industry with hydraulic drives.

## Roles & Responsibilities:

- Responsible for Raw Material purchasing (Hydraulic Products) from the USA, China & Europe.
- Forecasting the material as per customer requirement and market demand. Responsible for demand planning and forecast planning.
- Perform Transactional activities like Purchase order creation and Amendments.
- Monitor shipments for on-time departure and accurate arrival times. And information from purchase order creation to warehouse delivery is then conveyed to various in-house departments.
- Export & Import Air & Sea Freight negotiation (LCL/FCL), Coordination with CHA for Clearance and negotiation of CFS Charges, Preparation of Export & Import documentation.
- Process Export import documentation accurately and sent to appointed freight forwarders accurately and on time. Accuracy and timeliness of documents created cost savings avoiding any late fees or penalties.
- Prepare and process export-import documentation according to customs regulations, laws, and customs procedures.
- Provide the classification of goods, vehicles, test equipment, research equipment, personal effects (Expatriate transitions), samples, or any other item shipped from country-country using the Harmonized Tariff Schedule (HTS) and/or Schedule B by means of lookup and research.
- Determine the ECCN of exported goods through a similar methodology and include them in the electronic support packets.
- Classify material with BIS standard and smooth custom clearance formalities without any penalty and demurrage charges.
- Evaluated internal procedures and worked with Logistics to minimize detention and demurrage
- Worked closely with warehouse personnel to ensure timely delivery and receipt of products.
- Responsible for exporting the material from India to a different country and preparing advance licenses for each customer.
- Coordinate DGFT for custom-related work. Responsible for an Advance license, EPCG license, and MEIS license.
- Gathered and analyzed supplier, inventory, and distribution data to assess areas in need of improvement.

#### **Student Counsellor**

## **Headstart Education and Career, Ahmedabad**

June 2018 – August 2018

Company Profile (Brief): HeadStart is a leading overseas education consultant and has a global footprint with associates and world-recognized universities in Australia, the UK, Germany, France, Switzerland, Netherlands, Poland, Canada, Singapore, and NZ, and many other countries.

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Counselled and assessed the needs of prospective students to prepare graduation plans designed to achieve personal, professional, or academic goals.
- Built strong rapport with students to provide conflict resolution tools.
- Communicated with prospective and enrolled students via email and telephone using software database systems to track student progress.
- Interacted with other relevant departments to boost student success using financial aid, academic advising, and providing success coaches.

#### **EDUCATION**

- PGDM Finance from NMIMS Global School for Continuing Education | 2021 Till Date
- ❖ B.com (Hons.) in International Business | The IIS University, Jaipur | 2015 – 2018 | 2015
- XII (RBSE) | Arya Putri School, Ajmer

#### **CERTIFICATION**

- Supply Chain Logistics Rutgers University via Coursera
- Supply Chain Sourcing Rutgers University via Coursera
- Supply Chain Operations Rutgers University via Coursera
- Fundamentals of Quantitative Modelling Wharton University of Pennsylvania via Coursera
- ❖ Advanced Google Analytics via Google Analytics Academy
- Certification in Travel and Tourism The IIS University

# **Key Skills**

Material Planning	Supply Chain Management	Strategic Planning & Sourcing
SAP MM Module	Import & Export	ERP Knowledge
Material Procurement	Inventory Control	System Implementation
Advanced Excel	<ul> <li>Tableau</li> </ul>	Team Management

**Personal Information** 

: 02<sup>nd</sup> July, 1997 Date of Birth

Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English and Hindi